Guide to the William Zinsser Papers ca. 1946-1998 MSS.031
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I: Letters
  - Subseries D, Regarding his other books
    - Letters: Weekend Guests (Harper, 1963) (Box 2, Folder 64b.)
    - Letters: The Haircurl Papers (Harper, 1964) (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Letters: Pop Goes America (Harper, 1966) (Box 2, Folder 65a.)
    - Letters: The Paradise Bit (Little, Brown & Co., 1967) (Box 2, Folder 65b.)
    - Letters: The Lunacy Boom (Harper, 1970) (Box 2, Folder 65c.)
    - Letters: Writing With a Word Processor (Harper, 1983) (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Letters: Writing With a Word Processor (Harper, 1983) (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Letters: Writing With a Word Processor (Harper, 1983) (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Letters: Willie & Dwike (Harper, 1984) (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Letters: Willie & Dwike (Harper, 1984) (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Letters: Willie & Dwike (Harper, 1984) (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Letters: Writing to Learn (Harper, 1988) (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Letters: Writing to Learn (Harper, 1988) (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Letters: Writing to Learn (Harper, 1988) (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - Letters: Spring Training (Harper, 1989) (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Letters: American Places (HarperCollins, 1992) (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Letters: Speaking of Journalism (HarperCollins, 1994) (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Letters: Easy to Remember (Godine, 2001), early reactions and advice, 1996-2000 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Letters: Easy to Remember (Godine, 2001), 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Letters: Conversations, piano/saxophone CD, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Letters: Writing About Your Life (Marlowe, 2004), 2004-2006 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Letters: What's the Point, CD, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Subseries E, Regarding the Fales Library party at New York University
    - Letters: Regarding Fales Library event at NYU and NY Times article, undated (Box 2, Folder 78)
- Series II: Works by William Zinsser
  - Subseries A, Manuscripts
    - American Places, corrected manuscript, Chps. 1-7, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - American Places, corrected manuscript, Chps. 8-16 and "Acknowledgments", undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Any Old Place With You, corrected manuscript, Chps. 1-4, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Any Old Place With You, corrected manuscript, Chps. 5-6, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Any Old Place With You, corrected manuscript, Chps. 7-9, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - The City Dwellers, corrected manuscript, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Easy to Remember, corrected manuscript, undated (Box 3, Folder 6a.)
    - Easy to Remember, author's correction on first proof, undated (Box 3, Folder 6b.)
    - Easy to Remember, uncorrected proofs, undated (Box 3, Folder 6c.)
    - The Haircurl Papers, corrected manuscript, Chps. 1-6, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - The Haircurl Papers, corrected manuscript, Chps. 7-14, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - The Haircurl Papers, corrected manuscript, Chps. 15-20, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - How to Write a Memoir, audio tape, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 9a.)
    - The Lunacy Boom, corrected manuscript (1 of 2), undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - The Lunacy Boom, corrected manuscript (2 of 2), undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Mitchell and Ruff, author's correction (first published as Willie and Dwike), undated (Box 3, Folder 11a.)
    - On Writing Well (1st ed.), corrected manuscript, Chps. 1-12, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - On Writing Well (1st ed.), corrected manuscript, Chps. 13-17 and "Sources", undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - On Writing Well (2nd ed.), corrected manuscript, Chps. 1-11, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - On Writing Well (2nd ed.), corrected manuscript, Chps. 12-18 and "Bibliography", undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - On Writing Well (5th ed.), corrected manuscript, Chps. 1-13, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - On Writing Well (5th edition), corrected manuscript, Chps.14-22, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - On Writing Well (6th edition), revision of 5th ed. ms, Chps. 1-17, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - On Writing Well (6th ed.), revision of 5th ed. ms, Chps. 18-24 and "Sources", undated (Box 3A, Folder 19)
    - On Writing Well (6th ed.), corrected manuscript, Chps. 1-14, undated (Box 3A, Folder 20)
    - On Writing Well (6th ed.), corrected manuscript, Chps. 15-24, undated (Box 3A, Folder 21)
    - The Paradise Bit, corrected manuscript, Chps. 1-6, undated (Box 3A, Folder 22)
    - The Paradise Bit, corrected manuscript, Chps. 7-11, undated (Box 3A, Folder 23)
    - The Paradise Bit, corrected manuscript, Chps. 12-16, undated (Box 3A, Folder 24)
    - The Paradise Bit, corrected manuscript, Chps. 17-20, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Pop Goes America, corrected manuscript, Chps. 1-6, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Pop Goes America, corrected manuscript, Chps. 7-11, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Pop Goes America, corrected manuscript, Chps. 12-17, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - The Road to Timbuktu (unpublished), corrected manuscript, Chps. 1-6, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - The Road to Timbuktu (unpublished), corrected manuscript, Chps. 7-13 and "Epilogue", undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Seen Any Good Movies Lately?, corrected manuscript, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Spring Training, corrected manuscript, Chps. 1-8, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Spring Training, corrected manuscript, Chps. 9-19, "Epilogue" and "Sources", undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Weekend Guests, corrected manuscript, undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Willie & Dwike, corrected manuscript, Chps. 1-5, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Willie & Dwike, corrected manuscript, Chps. 6-7, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Willie & Dwike, manuscript, 2 IBM DisplayWrite disks, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Writing With a Word Processor, corrected manuscript, undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Writing About Your Life, final manuscript, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Writing Places, final manuscript, 2008-10-01 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Writing Places, 4 CD set, 2009; 4 sound discs (cd) 4 CDs, 5 hours (Box 13)
    - Zinsser on Friday, manuscript from blog, 3 folders, 2010-2011 (Box 12, Folder 14-16)
    - On Writing Well and How to Write a Memoir, 3 CD set, 2003; 3 sound discs (cd) 3 CDs, 2.5 hours (Box 13)
  - Subseries B, Various writing projects
    - Book reviews and articles about books/writers, 1960-1996 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Travel articles - places (1 of 2), 1952-1997 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Travel articles - places (2 of 2), 1952-1997 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Profiles - people (1 of 2), 1960-1995 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Profiles - people (2 of 2), 1960-1995 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Free-lance articles and assorted pieces (1 of 3), 1956-1988 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Free-lance articles and assorted pieces (2 of 3), 1956-1988 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Free-lance articles and assorted pieces (3 of 3), 1956-1988 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - New York Herald Tribune articles (5) on Mau Mau War New York Herald Tribune articles on the South Seas, 1954, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Horizon articles, 1958-1967 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Saturday Evening Post articles, 1962-1967 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Look columns, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Life columns (1 of 2), 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Life columns (2 of 2), 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - New York Times, Home Section columns, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - National Refractory & Brake Co. articles and Annual Reprot (sic), 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - The Museum for Modern Art manuscript, unpublished article for Life, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Herald Tribune Days manuscript, unpublished memoir, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - The Car Nut manuscript, unpublished children's book, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - The Western as a Ritual Art Form of America, outline and notes for tv program, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Sunday television scripts, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Humor in Public Television: Is There Any Hope? report, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - On Writing Well audio script, Nov. 1990, undated (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Introduction to Landmarks Exhibit, Municipal Arts Society, manuscript, June 1965, undated (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Pamphlets and letters, Book-of-the-Month Club, NY Public Library, 1966-1997 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - 60th Anniversary Exhibit, Book-of-the-Month Club, NY Public Library (1 of 3), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - 60th Anniversary Exhibit, Book-of-the-Month Club, NY Public Library (2 of 3), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - 60th Anniversary Exhibit, Book-of-the-Month Club, NY Public Library (3 of 3), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Tour de Force, Town and Country, Apr. 1999, undated (Box 5, Folder 66a.)
    - The Healing Moment, Princeton Alumni Weekly, May 19, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 66b.)
    - A Christmas Memoir, Town and Country, Dec. 1999, undated (Box 5, Folder 66c.)
    - Field of Tin, The Atlantic Monthly, July/Aug. 2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 66d.)
    - Conversations with Arnold Roth and Bill Zinsser, Audio CD, undated (Box 5, Folder 66e.)
    - Articles, 2 folders, 1999-2009 (Box 12, Folder 12-13)
    - Work as songwriter and musician, 1999-2003 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Conversations: Arnold Roth & Bill Zinsser, 2001; 1 sound disc (cd) total time: 41.31 (Box 13)
    - What's the Point: A Musical Revue about a Summer Community, CD, 2003; 1 sound disc (cd) (Box 13)
  - Subseries C, Scrapbooks
    - Scrapbook: Education articles (mostly), New York Herald Tribune, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook I: Movie reviews/columns, New York Herald Tribune, 1954-1956 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Scrapbook II: Movie reviews, New York Herald Tribune, 1956-1957 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook III: Movie reviews/editorials, New York Herald Tribune, 1957-1958 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Scrapbook IV: Editorials/columns (article/subject list), New York Herald Tribune, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Subseries D, Reviews and press comments
    - Reviews and Press: Inventing the Truth (editor, 1st ed.), 1985 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    - Reviews and Press: Inventing the Truth (editor, 2nd ed.), 1987 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Reviews and Press: Extraordinary Lives (editor), 1988 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Reviews and Press: Spiritual Quests (editor), 1988 (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Reviews and Press: Paths of Resistance (editor), 1989 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Reviews and Press: Worlds of Childhood (editor), 1990 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - Reviews and Press: They Went (editor), 1991 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - Reviews and Press: Any Old Place With You, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 74)
    - Reviews and Press: Seen Any Good Movies Lately?, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - Reviews and Press: The City Dwellers, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 76)
    - Reviews and Press: Five Boyhoods, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 77)
    - Reviews and Press: Weekend Guests, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 78)
    - Reviews and Press: The Haircurl Papers, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - Reviews and Press: Pop Goes America, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - Reviews and Press: The Paradise Bit, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 81)
    - Reviews and Press: Annual Reprot (sic), 1969 (Box 7, Folder 82)
    - Reviews and Press: The Lunacy Boom, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - Reviews and Press: On Writing Well (1st and 2nd eds.), 1976, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 84)
    - Reviews and Press: On Writing Well (3rd, 4th, 5th eds.), 1985, 1990, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 85)
    - Reviews and Press: Writing With a Word Processor, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 86)
    - Reviews and Press: Willie & Dwike, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - Reviews and Press: Writing to Learn, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 88)
    - Reviews and Press: Spring Training, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 89)
    - Reviews and Press: American Places, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 90)
    - Reviews and Press: Speaking of Journalism, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Subseries E, Lyrics
    - Songs written by Zinsser, undated (Box 8, Folder 92)
- Series III: Biographical
  - Assorted awards, honors, biographical articles written about William Zinsser, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Biographical information, 2001-2004 (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Series IV: Teaching, Lectures and Workshops
  - Subseries A, Lecture notes, letters, and articles at Yale University, Branford College, the Fieldston School
    - Correspondence re job search for college teaching position, 1967-1970 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Letters re Editorship at Yale Alumni Magazine, 1970-1977 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Letters re Mastership at Branford College, Yale University, 1973-1979 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Non-Fiction course, Yale University (1 of 2), 1971-1975 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Non-Fiction course, Yale University (2 of 2), 1971-1975 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Humor Writing course, Yale University, Spring 1977-1978, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Letters from former writing students, Yale University, ca.1972-1987 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Writing course, the Fieldston School, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Letters from form Writing Students, Yale University - solicited by Mark Singer for On Writing Well 6th edition, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Subseries B Lecture notes, workshop requests, and articles regarding talks and workshops on writing
    - Talks & Workshops (1 of 3), 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Talks & Workshops (2 of 3), 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Talks & Workshops (3 of 3), 1976-1980 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Talks & Workshops (1 of 3), 1981-1984 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Talks & Workshops (2 of 3), 1981-1984 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Talks & Workshops (3 of 3), 1981-1984 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Talks & Workshops (1 of 3), 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Talks & Workshops (2 of 3), 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Talks & Workshops (3 of 3), 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Talks & Workshops (1 of 3), 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Talks & Workshops (2 of 3), 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Talks & Workshops (3 of 3), 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Talks & Workshops (1 of 3), 1991-1998 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Talks & Workshops (2 of 3), 1991-1998 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Talks & Workshops (3 of 3), 1991-1998 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Talks & Workshops, 1998-2004 (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Oversize Series II, subseries C
  - Scrapbook: Feature articles, New York Herald Tribune (oversize), 1948-1949 (Box 10, Folder 1)